还有多远
How much longer?
大概三百英里吧
300 miles, give or take.
几点能到维加斯
What time do we get to Vegas?
上午9点吗
9:00 a.m.?
杂物箱里有餐巾纸
There's napkins in the glove box.
巨人
结语不错  有神秘感
Nice ending. Mysterious.
吊他们的胃口
Leave 'em wanting more.
我们紧张个什么劲啊
Why are we freaking out about this, anyway?
这是场展销会
I mean, it's a trade show.
他们想要巨人  压力大的该是他们
They want the Giant. The pressure's on them.
你以为那些分销商
Okay, you think thousands of vendors
会神奇地聚在我们展位前吗
are just gonna magically swarm our booth?
-当然了  会排起长队的  -重点不在展位
- Hell, yes. Get in line. - The booth isn't the point.
那只是用来辨别真正的买家
That's just a way to identify the real buyers
然后拉去我们的套房
and then get them up to our suite.
参加首展晚会派对
For the opening night party.
没错  套房里的才是重头戏
Yeah, suite's where the action is.
交易都是在那里敲定的
It's where we nail down all the real deals.
大家都很忐忑
Everybody's terrified.
没人知道哪种技术能赢得青睐
Nobody knows which technology's gonna win.
你的朋友想坑你
Oh, your friends are trying to rip you off.
敌人对你示好
Your enemies are buying you drinks.
竞争很激烈  乱极了
It's a catfight. It's total chaos.
简直是资本主义的最高境界
It's capitalism at its finest.
在苏格兰群岛
In the Scottish Isles,
人们在一年中最冷的那天庆祝节日
they hold a festival on the coldest day of the year.
镇上的人穿上维京人的服装
The town's people dress up in Viking costumes
分组比赛
and compete in squads,
载歌载舞  纵情畅饮
drinking and singing and dancing.
最后到午夜
Finally at midnight,
他们会来到位于镇广场的巨型木船前
they march up to a huge wooden ship in the town square.
然后呢
Then what?
胜者们会把船烧毁
Then the winners burn it to the ground.
你跟我们说这个干嘛
Why the hell did you just tell us that?
欢迎来到83年计算机分销商展览
早上好  登记入住吗
Good mning. Checking in?
卡迪夫电子
Cardiff Electric.
我们在9楼订了一间三卧套房
We have a three-bedroom suite on the ninth floor.
好的  请您先填写一下登记卡
Excellent. If you'd just fill out your registration card.
抱歉  您刚才说卡迪夫吗
I'm sorry, did you say Cardiff?
-是啊  -失陪一下
- That's right. - Excuse me for one moment.
-我是经理  -我是约翰·博斯沃思
- I'm the manager. - Uh, John Bosworth.
-有问题吗  -恐怕是有
- Is there a problem? - I'm afraid so.
我们今早刷了您的信用卡  但是被拒付了
We ran your card this morning and it was declined.
我们打了电话  但是没人接听
We tried to call, but no answer.
很不幸  我们只能取消了您预约的房间
Unfortunately, we had no choice but to release your room.
太荒谬了
That's absurd.
-我要给信用卡公司打电话  -我们已经打了
- Let me call the credit card company. - We already did.
您的公司账户被冻结了
Your corporate account has been frozen...
因为要接受刑事调查
due to a pending criminal investigation.
那就刷我的卡吧
Here, take a personal card.
刷这张绝对没问题
You won't have any problem with this.
"乔瑟夫·麦克米伦"
"Joseph MacMillan."
您不是约翰·博斯沃思吗
I thought you were John Bosworth.
能付钱不就行吗
If I can pay, what does it matter?
抱歉  房间都订满了
I'm sorry, we're fully booked.
我可以每晚再加200块
I'm willing to add a $200 premium per night.
等着要那间房的就有30个人
I have a waiting list 30 names long for that room.
没犯法的正经人
Legitimate names.
现在怎么办
So, what now?
展位没了
We lost our booth.
楼层经理说他也许能给我们挤出个位置
The floor manager said he might be able to squeeze us in.
我20分钟后就得答复
I'm supposed to get back to him in 20 minutes.
正好给了我们找其他酒店的时间
Well, that gives us time to find another hotel.
展会就在隔壁
The expo's right next door.
离开主街我们就失去了据点和人气
We move off the Strip, we lose our base, all our walk-in traffic.
欢迎宴会就在今晚  所有人都住在这儿
Our welcoming party's tonight. Everyone stays here.
但都订满了  我们能怎么办  贿赂吗
But it's booked. What are we supposed to do, bribe somebody?
-我试过了  -我们可是在拉斯维加斯
- I tried that. - Christ, we're in Las Vegas.
有一万一千美金现款
We have $11,000 in cash.
我们就不能想想办法吗
Can we get off our asses and make a move?
质子打印机  1475套房
Hey, Protonix Printers, suite 1475.
那对桑尼维尔市的兄弟  记得吗
Those brothers from Sunnyvale, remember?
不记得
No.
81年展会上他们大概和我们隔六个展位
They were, like, six booths away from us in '81.
我记得他们的演示  糟透了
I remember their demo. It sucked.
打给楼层经理  安排会面
Call the floor manager. Set the meet.
不管位置在哪  价格多贵
I don't care where it is or how much it costs,
拿到展位就行
just get us a booth.
你找来你最好的蓝色西装去洗手间换上
You, find your best blue suit and change in the bathroom.
-我们要干嘛  -在这里搞到个房间
- What are we doing? - We're gonna make room in the inn.
来吧  赶紧的
Come on, hustle up.
在文本模式下  打印机是逻辑查找的
In text mode, the printer is logic-seeking.
你一定会问  这是什么意思
What do I mean by that, you ask?
盛会大师  质子打印机
这意味着它的打印头可以双向移动
I mean it can print with its head moving in both directions.
是的  你没听错
Yes, you heard that right.
你的MX-80点阵打印机
Now, your average dot matrix printer, your DMP,
爱普生1980年推出的经典打印机
限制了你打印成品的大小必须符合标准
your MX-80, restricts you to a standard output size.
这适用于打印商业信函
Which is fine for business letters
和普通会计材料等等
and general accounting and such...
但那些更私人化的情况呢
But what about those moments that demand a more personal touch?
这就是盛会大师大展身手之机了
That's where the OccasionMaster steps in.
预先设定的字体  气球和动感的图形
With our pre-set fonts and balloons and sparkles graphics,
一定会给你最亲爱的人另一番感受
your near and dearest are guaranteed a special feeling.
来看结果吧  分发些样品  小皮
Result-- let's pass out those samples, Petey.
从露天招待会到单身派对
From the garden party to the bachelor party,
盛会大师是真正的...
the OccasionMaster is truly...
庆典大师
Your master of ceremonies.
本意为司仪
有什么问题吗
Any questions?
串行还是并行接口
Serial port or parallel?
现在只有并行接口
Well, it's just parallel for now,
但我们希望能在未来改进这一点
but that's something that we hope to upgrade in the future.
你们要价多少
And you're asking how much for it?
九百美元不含税
Oh, uh, $900 plus tax.
每秒打印字符数是多少
What's the CPS rate?
80到100吧  不一定
It's 80 to 100, depending.
所以说我花了一千块
So, I'm supposed to pay a thousand dollars
还要等上20分钟才能打印一封我只要花5分钟
to wait 20 minutes for that thing to spit out a thank-you note
就能写好的感谢信
when I can write my own in five?
每秒打印100个字符已经相当快了
100 CPS is quite fast, my friend.
但也没快得像闪电啊
Yeah, well, let's not act like it's lightning.
尤其是打印图片的时候
Especially with the graphics.
你不能调整下打印头让它更快些吗
Can't you modify the head to go any faster?
我们一直在测试盛会大师
We've been testing the OM
至今没有发现什么问题
with no problems for some time now.
-展示一下吧  -打印点什么
- Show us. - Yeah, print something.
好吧  你希望它更快点吗
Fine, you want it faster?
我还希望它能更便宜点
Well, I'd like it cheaper, too.
我听说IBM要推出一种
You know, I hear IBM's coming out with
多规格送纸打印机
a multiple format paper feed.
你哪听说的
Where'd you hear that?
我不该跟你们说的  但是
I'm not supposed to tell you this, but...
明年年初  我们就会发布一款多规格打印机
We are coming out with a multiple format printer first of the year.
如果我是你  就不挡我们的道
If I were you, I'd get out of our way.
那怎么办  就这么收拾东西走人吗
What, just pack up and leave?
我们为这次展会投入了全部
We put everything into this.
我很喜欢你们这样的人来跟我们斗  真的
Look, I love when guys like you take us on, I really do.
几年前  德卢斯有位先生
A couple years ago, a gentleman out of Duluth
自己写了一个文字处理软件  做得非常好
developed his own word processor. Great features.
但跟我们的同类产品撞个正着
But it went head-to-head with DisplayWriter.
-然后呢  -他妻子跑了  房子没了
- What happened? - After his wife left him and he lost his house,
后来他开车撞进了图书馆
he drove his car into a library.
他好像还在北部一家精神病院里治疗呢
I think he's still recuperating in a mental hospital upstate.
可我们已经入住了
We already checked in.
我们的套房一直订到了这周末
The suite's paid up through the end of the week.
我或许能帮上忙
Maybe I can help.
我们包了两层却还是住得爆满
We rented two floors and we're still bursting at the seams.
还有人睡在地毯上呢
I got guys sleeping on the carpet.
我们IBM没准能接手你们的套房呢
You know, IBM might be able to take that suite off your hands.
全价
Full freight.
我可不是想坑你们
I'm not looking to screw you guys over.
如果我们抵了开支的话
If we could break even...
那也是一大笔钱
That would be huge.
-只不过  -不过什么
- Except... - What?
我们今晚订的筵席
The big spread we ordered for tonight.
只怕这钱你们也得包了
You'd have to eat that cost.
那些虾啊
All that shrimp.
什么虾
Shrimp?
简直是拦路抢劫
This is highway robbery.
我们的展位本该在中间的
Our booth was supposed to be in the middle.
你来晚了  而且支票跳票了
You're late and your check bounced.
剩这一个算你运气好
You're lucky I have this one left.
你  赶紧下来  找摔呢
Hey, get down from there before you hurt yourself.
你订的用具都在这儿了
All of your material as ordered.
等等  我需要更多墙面
Wait, I need more wall space.
这这么一块破围板地方哪够啊
I can't fit all this on one crummy backing.
不关我事  女士
Not my problem, lady.
-要免费软件吗  -我的天
- Free software? - Jesus.
免费软件
Free software.
这倒也算个挣钱的法子
That's one way to make a living.
她们可不靠这个挣钱
No, that's not their living.
她们都是艳星  兼职"展会宝贝"
They're porn stars moonlighting as "Booth babes."
维加斯知道搞电脑的从不赌博
Vegas figured out that computer types don't gamble,
所以就在隔壁开了个黄片大会
so they schedule a porn convention next door.
年年与展会同期
Same time every year.
不是说套房里的才是重头戏吗
I thought the action was in the suites.
要是不引起他们注意
Yeah, well, no one's coming
谁又会去你的套房呢
to our suite if we don't get their attention.
怎么了
What?
你想干什么
What are you doing?
这样  我想法把他们拉到派对上
Look, I'll get them to the party,
你负责办个好派对  明白吗
you make sure it's one to remember, okay?
-谢谢你  -你好啊
- Thank you. - Hi. How are you?
负5  负12  等等
Minus five. Minus 12, wait.
-正5  -到底怎么了
- plus five. - Bottom line, please.
-开不了机  -暂时而已  也许没大事呢
- It won't start. - Yet. Yet, okay? It's probably nothing.
我们需要抗静电的工作间
What we need is an antistatic workstation.
把你鞋脱了  不是电源的问题
Take off your shoes. It's not the power supply.
收拾一下  去卧室里鼓捣
Pack it up. We're moving into the bedroom.
手提箱里有巨人  来诺威克套房1475开眼界
-喷漆干什么用的  -润色一下
- What is that for? - Touch-ups.
怎么了  出问题了吗  不能运行了
What? What's the matter? Is it not working?
暂时不能
Not yet.
什么意思  开不了机了
Meaning what, it won't boot up?
硬件上的事  你就别管了
Hardware issue. Not your problem.
麻烦你把衣服捡起来
Pick up those clothes, please?
一家小公司
"A small company...
背负着成不了大事的非议
No one expected it to be anything...
却终做出了伟大而非凡的成绩
evolved into something great, something magnificent."
不跟我们说说展位什么样吗
You gonna tell us how the booth looks?
会有人来吗
Is anyone coming?
我肯定会
I would.
-这里是卡迪夫电子吗  -是的
- Is this Cardiff Electric? - Yes. Yes, it is.
好的  真棒  我们上吧
Okay. All right. Let's do it, man.
真壮观
Radical.
-好诶  -快看这个
- Yeah! - Hey, check this out.
卡迪夫电子
我能再来三杯吗
Hey, can I get three more?
-没问题  -多谢
- You got it. - Thanks.
伙计  准备好了吗
Hey! Hey, man, is it ready yet?
闲人勿入
-准备好了吗  -没有
- Is it ready yet? - No.
我是说  快了
I mean, almost.
你都这么说了两小时了
It's been "Almost" for two hours.
速度和效果不可兼得
You can have it fast or you can have it work.
你自己决定
It's up to you.
拜托  施乐好歹是份工作嘛
Oh, come on, Xerox is still a job.
对帕洛阿尔托研究中心
Not at PARC,
那些发明以太网的人来说不是
not to the guys who created Ethernet.
这是纯粹的研究和实验
This is pure research and experimentation.
唐娜·克拉克
Donna Clark.
沃利·特纳  天哪  多久没见了
Oh, Wally Turner. My God, how long has it been?
你那时候刚怀了琼妮
You were pregnant with, uh-- with Joanie.
我现在有个新项目  写图
Hey, I got this new program-- GraphWrite.
界面是全彩的
It's productivity fare,
可以用各种大小的饼图和柱图显示数据
sizable pie charts and histograms, all in full color.
我说真的  你得去看看
I'm serious. You have to see it.
看什么
See what?
你们做的不都是机密吗
I mean, isn't everything you guys do top secret?
没错
You're right.
我不该和你说元类的事
I shouldn't tell you about meta-classing
或者超文本  又或者面向对象编程
or hypertext or object-oriented programming.
少来了
Stop.
戈登呢
Hey, where's Gordon?
他应该就来了
Oh, he should be out any minute.
真羡慕你俩还一起工作
Love that you two are still working together.
好多夫妻因为工作生活不能调和而分手了
So many couples that break up over the home life-work life thing.
我见过好多回了
I've seen this a million times.
但是你俩撑过了大风大浪
But you guys, you've weathered the storm.
恭喜你们的巨人
Hey, congrats on the Giant.
巨人  巨人  巨人
Giant! Giant! Giant!
还是无法装载  我可以重新配置驱动
It's not mounting. I can reconfigure the drive,
但是得花点时间
but that's gonna take time.
他们等不了这么久了
They're not gonna wait much longer.
唐娜  我当然知道了
Donna, I'm well aware of that.
太晚了  我们就这么上吧
It's too late. We go without it.
等下  你不用样机就去做演示吗
Wait, you're gonna do the demo without the demo?
这儿是拉斯维加斯  戈登
It's Las Vegas, Gordon.
-什么  乔  -该糊弄人了
- Wha-- Joe...? - Time to bluff.
等等  等等
Wait! Wait!
来  靠近点  都来看看  伙计们
Come on, get close. Check it out, guys.
想让我开机吗
You guys want me to turn it on?
就此时此刻吗
Right here, right now?
但是等一下
But wait a second.
等一下  等一下  等一下
Wait a second, wait a second, wait a second.
拉斯维加斯知道造一台电脑有多难
See, Las Vegas knows how hard it is to build a computer.
特别是这么一台又快又流畅的坏小子
Especially one as sleek and fast as our little bad boy right here.
但拉斯维加斯并不想知道
But Las Vegas doesn't want to hear
我们的886处理器比IBM XT快了70%
that our 886 processor is running 70% faster than the IBM XT.
它也不在乎我们的一体化液晶屏
It doesn't care that our integrated LCD screen
让巨人只有15磅重
makes the Giant a featherlight 15 pounds,
这小家伙便携  兼容  火辣得不行
that it's fully portable, fully compatible, and sexy as hell.
不  拉斯维加斯想让我们找乐子
No, Las Vegas wants us to have fun!
不然为什么我们隔壁
Why else would it schedule
就是世界上最大的成人片大会
the world's largest porn convention right next door?
这就不得不提到我们今晚的特邀嘉宾
Which leads me to our special guest tonight.
卡迪夫电子的贵宾
The Cardiff Electric VIPs.
4位来自大银幕的漂亮的年轻小姐
Four lovely young ladies direct from the cinema.
等等  我想先给大家看几张电子表格
Wait, wait, wait. I wanna show you guys some spreadsheets.
-不要  -那先看个文字处理软件吧
- No! - Come on, let's do some word processing.
什么  你们想看妹子吗
Wait, you wanna meet the girls now,
然后再看演示吗
before the demo?
好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
只要你们明天还来给我们捧场
Only if you all catch up with us tomorrow on the floor.
只要你们明天都来卡迪夫电子的展位
Only if you all show up at the Cardiff Electric booth
宿醉未醒  筋疲力尽
hungover, wrung out,
只为见证它在展会上一展风采
just to watch this machine smoke every box in COMDEX.
好吧  就这么定了
All right, it's a deal.
今晚  就让"巨人"来调动大家的兴致吧
So, tonight let's let the Giant turn you on.
永远别告诉女儿们我干了这事
Please never tell our daughters I was a part of this.
我才不会呢
Why would I?
卡迪夫电子
Cardiff Electric!
一般一年两次
Uh, usually, like, twice a year.
一次是为展览会  一次就是消遣
Once for COMDEX, once just for fun.
消遣  听起来真好
For fun -- that sounds really nice.
你一定得来
You have to come visit.
不是说达拉斯不好  电视里看着不错
Nothing against Dallas. It looks great on TV.
但是重头戏都在加利福尼亚
But California's where it's at.
而且你还这么年轻
And you're young.
-我考虑一下  -还有什么好考虑的
- I'll think about it. - What is there to think about?
-地震频发带  -我都感觉不到了
- Earthquakes. - I don't feel them anymore.
-邪教  连环杀手  -那是洛杉矶
- Cults? Serial killers? - That's all down in Los Angeles.
-感恩而死  -你太坏了
- The Grateful Dead. - Wow, you are mean.
乐队
我饿了  你想吃点薄饼吗
I'm hungry. You want some pancakes?
有人想吃薄饼吗
Hey, you guys want pancakes?
-薄饼  -当然
- Pancakes? - Hell, yeah.
-想要  -走吧
- Oh, yeah. - Let's go.
-走吧  -好
- Let's do it. - Yeah.
如果"巨人"真像你说的那样
If the Giant does everything you say...
我们或许可以考虑
it could be a contender for us.
你可别拿我寻开心  丹尼斯
Don't tease me if you're not for real, Dennis.
电脑天地有一千多家分店
ComputerLand has nearly a thousand branches.
连锁电脑零售店
电脑零售业就是我们发明的
We invented computer retail.
我保证我们是认真的
I can assure you, we're real.
那为什么要买德州一家无名小公司的特色产品呢
Then why buy a specialty product from a podunk firm in Texas?
你卖过车吗  乔
You ever sell cars for a living, Joe?
没有
No, never.
我就是卖车起家的
That's how I got started.
我学到的是如果你想卖旅行轿车
And I learned if you wanna sell station wagons,
橱窗里得先放辆跑车
you'd better have a sports car to park in the window.
很期待你们明天的展示
Looking forward to your demo tomorrow.
在转了  应该可以了
It's spinning. That should do it.
装载吧
Load 'er up.
太棒了
Yes.
终于好了
Finally.
你叫什么名字
感谢上帝
你好  感谢上帝  你想做什么
蜜月之后就再没这么做过了
Haven't done that since our honeymoon.
大学毕业之后就再没这么过了呢
Oh, I haven't done that since college.
什么  和谁做的
What? With who?
和谁啊
Who?
我们给他盖个毯子吧
Should we get him a blanket?
才不要  我们换个房间吧
Hell, no. We're switching rooms.
你真觉得它能大卖吗
Do you really think it'll sell?
如果展示成功的话
If we nail the demo.
那就太好了
This could be so good.
对女儿  对我们
For the girls, for us.
这些年我们都只是有一天过一天
For so long we've just gotten by.
感觉很奇怪吧
It's weird, huh?
这就叫成功吧
I think they call it success.
沃利·特纳来过  你见着他了吗
Wally Turner dropped by. Did you see him?
嗯  他向我推销了一通
Yeah, he cornered me with his sales pitch.
还是那个老样子
Still all about Wally.
我喜欢他软件的新点子
I like his new software idea.
是啊  我说会在"巨人"上试试的
Yeah, I told him we'd spec it out on the Giant.
沃利以为咱俩还是同事
Wally thinks we still work together.
是吗  你怎么说的
Yeah? What'd you tell him?
还能怎么说  我喜欢这份没前途的工作
What am I gonna say? I'm really enjoying my dead-end job
喜欢找老妈帮我看孩子吗
and having my mom raise my kids?
派对上说这个不合适吧
It's not exactly cocktail chatter.
你说什么呢  唐娜
What are you talking about, Donna?
这项目有多少次都多亏了你
You saved this project a dozen times.
没有你就造不出主板
We wouldn't have a motherboard without you.
没有你都造不出这台电脑
We wouldn't have an entire machine without you.
你心里是清楚
I know you know that.
那怎么着
Well, what?
你要来卡迪夫吗
You wanna join Cardiff?
近距离观看怪胎秀吗
Get a front-row seat to the freak show?
我可没那么说
I didn't say that.
但是呢
But?
你至少问问我也好啊
But it would've been nice if you'd asked.
是啊
You're right.
我是该问你的
I should have asked, but...
几个月前  我在"杀戮室"
look, a few months ago, I was in the Kill Room
一个人加班到很晚
and I was working late all by myself.
我突然意识到我们进展多慢
And it hit me, how far behind we were.
也意识到为了造"巨人"
And how hard I'd have to grind
我要付出多少
to get the Giant built.
就像跟人打赌爬悬崖
And it was like climbing a cliff on a dare,
碰到了悬垂上不去
where you hit an overhang and you can't go up,
爬下去又太陡  这时...
and it's too steep to climb back down. And...
你才意识到
you realize
"跳"的真正含义
what the word "jump" really means.
如果我握着你的手  数到三
And if I held your hand and counted to three...
我不确定你肯不肯一起跳
I wasn't sure you'd come with me.
我们结婚了  戈登
We're married, Gordon.
我们已经跳了
We already jumped.
是啊
Yeah.
那是什么
What's that?
胡佛大坝的碎块
A piece of the Hoover Dam.
你知道我为什么喜欢它吗
You know what I like about it?
因为它没有电路和电线
There's no circuits or wires.
非常简单
It's so simple.
表里如一
It is what it does.
玩得开心吗
Did you have fun?
吃了薄饼
I ate pancakes and
跟施乐的小伙子们看了日出
watched the sun come up with the Xerox boys.
居然没闹没疯吗
That sounds entirely too wholesome.
博斯沃思来找我的时候
When Bosworth came to me...
我应该去找你的
I should've come to you.
卡梅伦
Cameron...
他们
California--
加州那边的工作  真的很厉害
what they're doing out there, it's really impressive.
也许你该去帕罗奥图[硅谷]Maybe you should go to Palo Alto.
也许我们是该去
Maybe we should.
戈登  你真需要再弄一件AMD的T恤吗
Gordon, do you really need another AMD T-shirt?
超微半导体公司
是啊  这是今年新款
Yeah, this is this year's.
Windows系统不错嘛
Hey, Windows looks cool.
是啊  但全是漏洞
Oh, yeah, but it was crawling with bugs.
我就是忘不掉惠普的触屏
I can't get over HP's touch screen.
是啊  肯定会...
Yeah, it's a fad...
-快看快看  -流行起来的
- Oh, look, look, look. - ...guaranteed.
高密度软盘
High-density floppy disks.
这边很火爆啊
Oh, someone's hot.
我们去看看吧
Let's check it out.
看什么啊
Why?
他们马上就都会被吸引去我们的展位了
They'll be down at our booth in, like, 60 seconds.
那么我问问大家
And so I ask you,
如果要卖车才能买得起
what is the point of a revolution
这种革命还有何意义
if you have to sl your car to afford it?
这不是在演《杰森一家》Now, this isn't "The Jetsons."
设置在未来的科幻动画片
我们不是要卖外星枪给你
We're not selling you a ray gun.
我们想呈现一款简单
We're trying to give you the simplest product
又极其灵活的产品
with the most flexibility.
想要硬盘支持  插上就好
You want hard disk support? Plug it in.
大显示器  我们的字体能自动调整
A bigger monitor? Our fonts adjust automatically.
当然  我们觉得现在也挺好
Of course, we think they're just fine as is.
8086处理器
8086 processing,
双面主板
a doubleided motherboard...
-唐娜  -功能多样
- Donna... - ...packed with functionality.
强劲  迅速  简单
So strong, so fast, so simple,
居然以前都没人想到
it's a wonder no one thought of it before.
弹弓
The Slingshot.
弹弓  新  快  简单  强劲
哥利亚也最终发现
Because, as Goliath found out,
《圣经》中被大卫杀死的巨人
胜利不属于敏捷或强壮的人
victory goes not to the swift, nor to the strong,
而属于先下手的那小子
but to the little guy who strikes first.
有问题吗
Any questions?
你这个混蛋
Damn you, you son of a bitch!
-唐娜  -我杀了你
- Hey, Donna! - I'm gonna kill you--
-别碰他  -唐娜  走吧
- Get off him! - Donna, come on.
唐娜  算了  走吧
Donna, let's go, come on.
没事了
Okay, okay.
报复挺不好受吧
Payback's a bitch.
他们抄了我们的电脑  肯定得有设计图啊
But they copied our machine. They need schematics for that.
这是商业间谍行为
This is corporate espionage.
我得查清他们偷了什么  造成多大损失
I need to know what was compromised and the extent of the damage.
-别进来  -什么
- Out. - What?
我从没把任何东西拿去德州仪器
I never brought anything to T.I.
我接过电话
There were phone calls.
或许他听到了什么
Maybe he overheard--or-- or that--
-你寄到酒店的传真  -你跟他上床了吗
- the fax you sent to the hotel.  - Are you sleeping with him?
回答我
Answer the question.
-你在跟他上床吗  -没有
- Are you sleeping with him? - No.
我吻过他  就一次
I kissed him, once.
你吻了他  不是倒过来吗
Yeah, you kissed him and not the other way around?
是的  戈登  我吻了他
Yeah, Gordon. Yeah, I kissed him.
那两秒半里
And for two and a half seconds,
我比这两年来都快乐
I felt better than I've felt in two years.
天呐  唐娜  你真幼稚
Christ, Donna, you're a child.
根本没什么幼稚可言
There was nothing childish about it.
-我想要他  而且我有原因  -唐娜
- I wanted him, and there were reasons. - Donna, he--
-唐娜  -这些原因源自你我之间的问题
- Donna-- - There were you-and-me reasons
因为你不能假装
because you can't pretend we were
-我们之间一切都好  -他利用了你
- on some moonlit carriage ride. - He used you! He used you!
至少他鼓动还回报了我
At least he encouraged me and rewarded me.
你真相信他吗  你被蒙蔽了  唐娜
You believe that? You're blind, Donna.
你根本看不清他的真正目的
You never even saw what he was doing!
你从来不曾对我有任何的帮助
And you never even picked me up out of a hole in the ground.
我帮过你那么多次  照顾你和孩子
I lifted you up so many times. I carried you and the kids.
我那么累  那么难过  你却毫不在乎
And I was tired and miserable and you didn't give a shit.
我们之间没什么  但本该有什么的
It wasn't an affair, but it should've been.
好啊  去吧  你既然都决定了
All right. Go on, then. You've made your decision.
-天呐  -你去前台
- Oh, my God. - You go down to the front desk
问他住哪
and you ask for his suite number!
他一定会给你腾地方的
I'm sure he'll make room for you!
难道你就不是
Like you didn't pick the Giant over me
总把巨人放在我之前吗
every second of every single day.
唐娜  你真老套
Oh, my God, Donna. Donna, you're a clich?
你们俩  就是我们的努力成果的廉价山寨
Both of you. Just a cheap rip-off of something that we built together.
-我倒想去  但已经没机会了  -是吗  去啊
- I would go, but it's all ruined for me now, - Yeah? Go.
-你就想如此  -去吧
- because that's what you want. - Go.
你宁可正确  而不是要我
You want to be right more than you want me.
唐娜  或许你父母就是看对我了
You know what, Donna? Maybe your parents were right about me.
我就是个狭隘  小气  怨愤的暴君
I'm just a small-minded, petty, resentful little tyrant.
有时候是酒鬼  永远是个废物父亲
You know, part-time alcoholic, full-time failure as a father!
但我清楚我们曾经的感情  唐娜
But I knew what I had with you, Donna.
而且我一直在努力对得起这份感情
And I never stopped trying to live up to that.
对你  唐娜  我从未放弃过
To you, Donna. To you, I never, ever gave up.
他们改主意了
They changed their mind.
我们的操作系统  我们的设计  他们才不管
Our dynamic OS, our design-- they don't care.
他们就想要旅行轿车
They want a station wagon.
弹弓更快  更便宜
The Slingshot's faster, it's cheaper.
我们没戏了
So we're dead.
听到了吗  戈登
Did you hear that, Gordon?
他们圣诞就能上架
They'll be in stores by Christmas.
我真替你难过
My heart goes out to you.
我能想象这多令人痛心
I know how painful this must be.
但两条道路交汇时
But when two paths converge,
不管是有意还是无意
intentionally or not,
他们未必会一起延续下去
they don't always continue on together.
一条路向前推进
One peels off,
另一条到此为止
the other dead-ends.
就别扯什么"林子里的两条路"了
Let's skip the "Two Roads in a Wood" bullshit.
指罗伯特·弗罗斯特的诗《未选之路》
你又不是罗伯特·弗罗斯特
You're not Robert Frost.
你就是当铺的小工
You're pawnshop hacks
把我的梦想廉价包装卖掉
selling my dream under a cheap plastic mask.
早听说你这人挺敏感
I heard you were touchy.
液晶屏  哪找来的  台湾货船吗
That LCD screen, where did you find it, a Taiwanese barge?
向我们道歉  撤掉你们的产品
Apologize, pull your product,
我或许不会告你
and I'll consider not suing.
诉诸法律毫无好处  乔
There's no upside to litigation, Joe.
等我们真上了法庭
By the time you get in front of a jury,
我们第三代产品都出了
we'll be on our third generation.
而且你们的BIOS不也是克隆IBM
And good luck persuading them that your BIOS
你要怎么让陪审团觉得这就比我们强
is such a nobler copy of IBM's than ours.
我们先做到了  认栽吧
We got there first. Deal with it.
你一定很自豪吧
You must be proud.
雇我们不要的人  从对手妻子那儿打探秘密
Hiring our sloppy seconds, pumping a competitor's wife.
这么做生意真行
That's one way to do business.
机会自己送上门的
The opportunity presented itself.
我没有犯法
No laws were broken.
难道你不会这么做吗
Are you telling me you'd do different?
-给我小心点  -得了吧
- I'd be more careful. - Oh, please.
你们高级副总裁在面临指控
Your SVP's under indictment,
你跟你的主程序员上床
you're sleeping with your lead coder,
更别提阿蒙克的那件事
not to mention that little incident back in Armonk.
我说得对不对
Let me see if I get this right.
你跟你父亲起了争执
Following an argument with your father,
随后你就损坏了总水管
you ruptured a water main,
淹了一个IBM的数据中心
flooded an entire IBM data center?
爸爸一定把你气得不轻吧
Daddy musta made you pretty angry.
没错  我查过你的底
Oh, yeah. I did my homework on you, all right.
纽约"喜欢"你的人不少呢
You got quite the fan club back there in New York.
认得这个号码吗
You recognize that number?
那是你老板内森·卡迪夫的号码
That's your boss, Nathan Cardiff.
你上楼去给他打电话
Now, you're gonna go upstairs, you're gonna call him,
告诉他我出两百万
and tell him that I offered you $2 million
弹弓的股份买巨人
in Slingshot stock for the Giant.
这可比和解你能拿到的钱多多了
Which is more than you're gonna get in the settlement.
我们为什么要卖给你们
Why would we sell to you?
因为这能填补你们开发用钱留下的坑
'Cause that covers your R&D nut, gets you out whole
否则你们会坐失一切
as opposed to losing everything for nothing.
然后你把我们拆了散卖吗
Then you strip us for parts?
那台电脑还是有些可取之处的  乔
There's some good ideas in that machine, Joe.
你错就错在爱上了那个
Your mistake was falling in love with
互动操作系统
that precious query-based interface.
它或许是很超前  但太占内存
Maybe it's ahead of its time, but it's a memory hog.
我们绝不会卖给你
We'll never sell to you.
等我们跟电脑天地签约  这就是标配了
After we sign with ComputerLand, it's academic.
接不接受随你吧
Take it or not.
告诉唐娜  别往心里去
Oh, and tell Donna it wasn't personal.
我真替你遗憾  惠特马什先生
I feel sorry for you, Mr. Whitmarsh.
你骗了你自己
You cheated yourself.
你永远造不出属于你自己的东西
You'll never create anything of your own.
你不也一样
Well, neither will you.
别忘了  我们做的是兼容机
You seem to have forgotten, we're in the compatible business.
你想出类拔萃
You tried to be good.
可我们做到差不多就行了
We just had to be good enough.
说来好笑
You know, it's funny--
同样的酒  付了五块钱
it's funny how much better it tastes
味道就好多了
when you've paid five bucks for it.
怎么样了
How are we doing?
挺好的
Fine, I guess.
我把子板和附加的内存都拆了
I stripped out the daughter board and all the extraneous memory.
我叫卡梅伦
指令或文件名错误
我的操作系统呢
Where's my operating system?
沃利借了我微软磁盘操作系统
Wally lent me MS-DOS.
这样比弹弓快  还便宜一百块
It'll beat the Slingshot on speed and be a hundred bucks cheaper.
你给拿出来了
You took it out.
你拿走了让它独特的东西
Everything that made it unique.
我们之前有个麻烦  现在我们有产品了
We had a problem. Now we have a product.
你不能让他这么做
You can't let him do this.
乔  说话啊
Joe. Tell him.
他错了  这样不对
He's wrong. This is wrong.
这对电脑是正确策略
It's what's right for the machine.
天呐
Oh, my God--
-这是为了生存  -别跟我说话
- It's called survival. - Don't speak to me.
是为了维持下去
It's an existential choice.
按原样是卖不动的  这个能买上百万
Sell none of the original or a million of these.
但没人会记住它的
And no one will remember a single one.
-它还是我们的啊  -那是个空壳
- It's still our machine. - It's empty.
今天结束之前我们得做展示  否则就完了
We need to demo by the end of business or we're dead.
-我需要你也去  -滚吧
- I need you there. - Bullshit!
好吧  那...我想要你去呢
Okay, how about... I want you there?
我想要你跟我一起去
I want you with me.
那就装回去
Then put it back in.
你会发现不管是Multiplan还是Lotus 1-2-3
You'll see that whether it's Multiplan or Lotus 1-2-3,
微软早期电子制表软件
巨人能运行所有商业软件
the Giant runs all your business software
系统兼容  机身紧凑小巧
on one compact, compatible package.
下班之后呢
What happens when the workday ends?
你还能带上巨人回家
You pack up your Giant, bring it home,
只需五分钟  就能启动游戏给孩子玩
and in five minutes, fire up "Rocky's Boots" For the kids.
一款教育性逻辑益智游戏
我一直叫他小心鳄鱼的
I keep telling him, "Watch out for that alligator."
不管是创作音乐
Whether it's composing music
还是整理家庭理财
or cobbling together your family finances,
巨人都能帮你完成
the Giant is there.
它不仅是一个家庭成员  也是你生活的一部分
It's not just a part of your family, it's a part of your life.
有什么问题吗
Um, are there any questions?
听说它能问你问题  比如你的名字
I heard it asks you stuff, like it learns your name.
哪听说的
Where'd you hear that?
像是科幻小说
It sounds a little "Buck Rogers."
科幻小说《2419大决战》中的人物
那么说电脑速度快  能运行各种软件
So, it's fast and it runs all the software,
但除了便携  没有其他特别的了
but besides portability, I'm not seeing a lot that's special.
没什么独特之处
Nothing unique.
"独特"  这么说真有意思
"Unique." Interesting word choice.
你到底想要什么
What are you really asking for?
特别的东西吗  温暖可爱的东西吗
Something special? Give me something warm, something fuzzy?
这是一台机器
This is a machine.
它不是你的朋友  而是你的雇员
It's not your friend, it's your employee.
它为你工作
It works for you.
所以评价它的正确方式是
And the way it should be evaluated is thus--
"它能多快多好地完成我交待的任务"
"How well and how fast does it do the things I ask?"
回答是"立刻马上"  否则就是浪费你的时间
Answer-- "Instantly." Anything less is a waste of your time.
"错误率是多少"  回答"零"
"What is the margin of error?" Answer-- "Zero."
否则就是失败
Anything more and you've failed.
还有一个词  绝对比
Here's another word, one that's infinitely more important
"独特"要重要得多  "速度"
than "unique" will ever be-- "speed."
我们成熟一点  少说废话吧
Let's cut through the bullshit and act like adults.
你们想要速度
You want speed,
这台电脑就是最快的
and this machine is the fastest one you'll find, period.
要跟孩子玩游戏
You wanna play a game with your kid,
跟他一起做幼儿园手工制作吧
join him for craft time at preschool.
想要个朋友  买条狗吧
You want a buddy? Buy a dog.
想要追逐不切实际的梦想吗  走出去吧
You want to chase rainbows, tilt the room? Walk outside.
这里有几百家赌场
There are a hundred casinos out there
正是为你们这种爱做梦的
built for delusional people like you
自以为生活能轻易改变的人建造的
who think their world is gonna change so easily.
想要完成工作  那就买我们的电脑
You wanna get something done, buy one of these.
你怎么把这些东西都装下的
So, how did you get everything to fit?
主板两面都装芯片
Um, chips on both sides.
谁想到的主意
Who thought of that?
我妻子
My wife.
唐娜·克拉克
Donna Clark.
散热问题怎么解决的
How'd you fix the heat problem?
我们在侧板加了通风口  并调整了芯片排布
We vented the side panels and changed the chip layout.
开除你之后工作好做多了
It got a lot easier after we fired you.
那IBM呢
What about IBM?
听说他们也要生产便携电脑呢
I heard they might be coming out with a portable.
我受够了IBM
I'm sick of hearing about IBM.
IBM一天内抛弃的项目比我们一年内能尝试的还多
IBM scraps more projects in a day than any of us attempt in a year.
我们所做的工作更难
What we did was harder.
我们将一个想法执行到底
We took one idea all the way...
这让我们付出了代价
and it cost us.
让我们损失了很多人
It cost us people.
但这份代价的证明就在此
But the evidence of that cost is here.
就在硬件里
It's in the damn metal.
乔  我得承认
Joe, why, I gotta tell ya.
能把电脑的速度提升这么多的人
Any man who can speed up a machine by that much that fast
在个人电脑界前景一片光明啊
has got a very bright future in PCs.
谢谢  丹尼斯
Thank you, Dennis.
六万台  每台九百  如何
How does 60,000 units at, say, $900 a pop sound?
可以考虑
It's a start.
好吧  七万呢
Okay... 70,000.
我们明天再谈
We'll negotiate tomorrow.
酒是温的  得加冰
It's warm. Needs ice.
我去拿吧
I'll get it.
大家好  我是麦金托什
Hello, I'm Macintosh.
你没事吧  伙计  怎么了
You okay, man? What's the matter?
它说话了
It speaks.
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
潇湘月影
七七
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
小酸奶!
翻译
木浅薰
somehacker
翻译
草草
时间轴
Kallen 芒果树叶
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第九集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌